Defy reality.
Insurgent is a action, science fiction, thriller
film directed by Robert Schwentke.
Beatrice Prior must confront her inner demons and continue her fight against a
powerful alliance which threatens to tear her society apart.
Beatrice 'Tris' Prior, played by Shailene Woodley.
Tobias 'Four' Eaton, played by Theo James.
Peter Hayes, played by Miles Teller.
Jeanine Matthews, played by Kate Winslet.
Caleb Prior, played by Ansel Elgort.
Christina, played by Zoë Kravitz.
The Divergent Series: Insurgent (simply known as Insurgent) is a 2015 American dystopian science fiction action film directed by
Robert Schwentke, based on the 2012 novel Insurgent, the second book in the Divergent trilogy by Veronica Roth.
It is the sequel to the 2014 film Divergent and the second installment in The Divergent Series, produced by Lucy Fisher,
Pouya Shabazian and Douglas Wick, with a screenplay by Brian Duffield, Akiva Goldsman and Mark Bomback.
Schwentke took over from Neil Burger as director, with Burger
serving as the executive producer of the film.
Along with the first film's returning cast, led by Shailene Woodley and Theo James, the sequel features supporting actors Octavia Spencer,
Kate Winslet, Naomi Watts, Suki Waterhouse, Rosa Salazar, Daniel Dae Kim, Jonny Weston, Emjay Anthony, and Keiynan Lonsdale.
The plot of Insurgent takes place five days after the previous installment and continues to follow Dauntless soldier Tris Prior; Tris and Four,
her Dauntless instructor, are on the run after evading a coup from Erudite faction leader Jeanine and the rest of her faction.
The faction system in post-apocalyptic Chicago is crumbling, and
everyone is desperate for power — and answers.
Filming began on May 27, 2014, in Atlanta, Georgia,
before concluding on September 6, 2014.
The Divergent Series: Insurgent was released on March 20, 2015 by Lionsgate Films under its Summit
Entertainment label, in the United States in the IMAX 3D format as well as regular 3D and 2D.
Critical reaction to the film was mixed.
Some considered the film to be an improvement over its predecessor, with the visual style, action sequences, and Woodley's
performance being singled out for praise; criticism focused on the film's storyline and derivative nature.
The film was a commercial success, grossing $52.2 million in its opening
weekend and reaching the number one spot at the box-office.
During its release in theaters, the film earned $297.3 million
worldwide, becoming the highest-grossing film in the series.
A sequel, Allegiant, was released on March 18, 2016.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
revolution, dystopia, sequel, transhumanism.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.